Carlos Alberto de la Guardia Pirdra

Technology-inclined professional possesses strong troubleshooting capabilities and a customer-oriented attitude. Experienced in providing network and software support to users and developing and implementing technical solutions. Adept at analyzing system performance and security to drive optimal user experience.



PERSONAL INFO

EMAIL cdelaguardia1987@gmail.com

PHONE 8110696724

LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/carlos-alberto-de-la-guardia-piedra-b74556242/

WORK HISTORY

IT Support Specialist and Help Desk

INFOGA, SAN NICOLÁS DE LOS GARZA

2022-10 - PRESENT

2021-06 - 2022-07

In August 2022 I moved to Mexico to study at the Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León. After a while, I started working at Infoga, an Internet and electronic security service provider, located in Escobedo, Nuevo León.

- · Provide remote and on-site support for laptops, PCs, printers, mobile devices, and other equipment.
- Provide technical support for software or hardware maintenance and installation.
- · Diagnose and troubleshoot wireless network outages.
- · Installation and maintenance of CCTV systems.

Specialist in Telematics (Network Management Group)

ETECSA, SANTA CLARA, CUBA

In June 2021, a change was made in the organizational structure of the ETECSA Company, so I became a Telematics Specialist in the Network Administration Group. In this new position, in addition to the functions I had previously, I have had to assume new ones:

- Perform the supervision of the technological sites in the specialty of Transmission.
- · Participate in field tests for the introduction of new technologies and certify that they meet the requirements for operation.
- Participate in the identification of vulnerabilities in the telecommunications network, and propose actions to mitigate or eradicate

Specialist in Telematics (Operations Support Group)

ETECSA, SANTA CLARA, CUBA

2013-01 - 2021-05

After completing the period of job training, I held the position of Telematics Specialist, attending the engineering of the Network. In this position I have served:

- Carrying out studies of the different performance indicators of the telecommunications network and proposing actions to
 optimize the physical and logical resources that compose it to improve these indicators.
- Managing the processes of acceptance and start-up of the investments made, according to the protocols and standards of the specialties of Switching, Transmission, Tele-traffic, Access, and Energy
- I have managed to carry out projects that have solved existing service needs in remote rural communities by optimizing the use of equipment.
- Design and implementation of the GPON network in the Cayo Santa María Tourist Pole

Training Technician

2011-09 - 2012-09

ETECSA, SANTA CLARA, CUBA

In this period, I became acquainted with:

- · The Operation, Maintenance, and Homologation of Energy and Backup Systems for Telecommunications Equipment.
- The design and installation of Integral Protection Systems for Telecommunications equipment.
- Measurement and analysis of radio signal propagation
- Installation, Operation, Maintenance, and Solution of Faults of Radio-link equipment, mainly from the manufacturers Huawei, Nokia, and Ericsson.
- Characteristics and types of Fiber Optics.
- · Installation of Fiber Optic Networks, complying with technical standards.
- Measurements for Fault Detection in Fiber Optic Networks.

EDUCATION	
Telecommunications, Master Degree in Electrical Science UNIVERSIDAD AUTÓNOMA DE NUEVO LEÓN, SAN NICOLÁS DE LOS GARZA, NUEVO LEÓN, MÉXICO	2022-08 - PRESENT
Telecommunications, Diploma in Network Administration UNIVERSIDAD CENTRAL "MARTA ABREU" DE LAS VILLAS, SANTA CLARA, CUBA	2017-09 - 2018-07
Telecommunications, Degree in Telecommunications and Electronics Engineering UNIVERSIDAD CENTRAL "MARTA ABREU" DE LAS VILLAS, SANTA CLARA, CUBA	2006-09 - 2011-07
SKILLS	
Teamwork skills Self-learning Analysis and critical thinking Adaptation to new scenarios Logical and mathematical reasoning Hardware and software installations Networking Tools and Protocols	
SOFTWARE	
Office 365 Python MATLAB Wireshark software	
LANGUAGES	
Spanish English	****
COURSES	
Basic Course of IP/MPLS Networks	2013-03
TCP/IP network architecture. WAN Networks	2014-09
WLL Multigain Wireless Innowave ECI Telecom System. Operation and Maintenance	2015-11
DSLAM ALCATEL ISAM7302, 7330-735x. Management System 5520 AMS	2015-04
SDH-OSN Network Course (1500B, 2500, 3500, 7500)	0015.00

GPON - ZTE system. Basic Course for Network Engineering

2015-02

2015-01

Ī	SAP ERP MM Course. Materials Management	2016-05
ł	Huawei OptiX RTN-905 Equipment Operation and Maintenance Course	2017-06
ļ	Huawei WLAN. Planning and Design with SVA 3200	2017-09
ļ	Python Essenctials 1 and 2 by Cisco	2023-01
ļ	Data Fundamentals by IBM	2023-05
	English for IT by Cisco	2023-09
	Play it Safe: Manage Security Risks by Google on Coursera	2023-09
	Foundations in Cybersecurity by Google on Coursera	2023-09